We're here to take a quick look at the Amazon Tax Exemption Program.
After watching this video, you'll understand what the Amazon Tax Exemption Program is,
how to enroll, and how to get exemption certificates for your tax exempt sales.
The Amazon Tax Exemption Program, or ATEP, can make selling to tax exempt buyers a little
easier.
ATEP automates the process, applying applicable tax exemptions at the time of sale,
so you don't have to process a refund after the fact.
When a buyer makes a tax exempt purchase from a seller enrolled in ATEP, ATEP populates
the exemption certificate with the seller's legal entity name and the buyer's exemption
information.
Amazon then automatically processes the tax exemption for the sale.
ATEP also stores exemption certificates for tax exempt sales for future reference.
You can enroll in ATEP from your seller account by clicking the "Tax Settings" link under
the "Settings" drop-down menu.
From the "Tax Settings" page, click "View edit
your tax collection, obligations, and shipping and handling and gift wrap tax settings.
Here you can update your tax calculation settings to enroll in ATEP.
Note that there may still
be special cases where you'll need to execute a post-order refund such as non-ATEP FBA exempt
customers or freight forwarders.
Getting tax exemption certificates is easy
once you've enrolled in ATEP.
From your seller account, select the "Reports" tab, then "Tax
Document Library." Next, select the "Tax Exemption Certificates" tab.
Select either "Order ID" or "Date Range" to sort.
Once you've entered your search criteria, click "Get Report" to submit your request.
Keep in mind that certificates become available 48 hours after you have confirmed shipment
of your tax exempt order.
That does it for the Amazon Tax Exemption Program.
Thanks for tuning in.